Contact

55 61 992585694 (Mobile) thiago.sousa.lopes@gmail.co m

www.linkedin.com/in/thsl (LinkedIn) thsl.github.io/thsl/ (Portfolio) github.com/thsl (Other)

Top Skills

User Experience
User Interface Design
CSS

Languages

English (Full Professional)
Português (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Leadership Through Design Innovation

UX Research for Agile Teams
Digital Product Leadership

Digital Transformation

Data Leadership for Business

Honors-Awards

Prêmio efinance - Modernização de Canais, Novo Mobile Banking, Extra Cash Web":

Thiago Lopes

Product Designer (UX/UI especialist)

Federal District, Brazil

Summary

As a Senior User Experience and Strategic Designer, I have been working on projects in various companies and different segments, I have specialized in innovation strategies, participating at the beginning of the project creation process.

Using tools that help to reposition ideas, implementing prototypes, usability tests, and sometimes developing simple HTML and CSS coding.

My portfolio: https://thsl.github.io/thsl/

Experience

Sebrae

Senior Product Designer (UX/UI) - User Experience Design Specialist March 2019 - Present (4 years 3 months)

Brasília. Distrito Federal

Sebrae is a Brazilian autonomous social institution part of the Sistema S whose aim is to foster the development of micro and small enterprises, stimulating entrepreneurship in the country. Founded in 1972 with the name of Cebrae, it was an entity associated with the Brazilian federal government.

At Sebrae, as a senior UX Specialist, I have been designing interfaces for complex systems, apps, and sites used by thousands of users. Part of the work is improving the user experience, digital transformation, and UX strategy.

Design System - For Sebrae (a Huge company)

The big challenge was not just to build all the standards for user interfaces, but also to make a simple way to apply research studies, design ops, and always think about the experience for clients and providers.

Zazmic Inc Senior Product Designer Consultant

August 2022 - March 2023 (8 months)

Page 1 of 8

Ucrânia

Working as a Zazmic contractor (Zazmic is a development company) in Cision projects (Cision is a company with clients worldwide), I was responsible for the user experience, which included understanding the users, suggesting improvements, and creating/applying the complex system's visual design. Also, I've worked with the developers, helping to find the best solution for UX problems in the user interface.

DevSquad Senior Product Designer June 2022 - September 2022 (4 months) Inglaterra, Reino Unido

As a short time contractor, I've worked to Emerald Group, developing UX solutions for the website, and their publications;

FIOCRUZ - Fundação Oswaldo Cruz Senior Product Designer (UX/UI) June 2018 - March 2022 (3 years 10 months) Brasil

The Oswaldo Cruz Foundation (Portuguese Fundação Oswaldo Cruz, also known as FIOCRUZ) is a scientific institution for research and development in biological sciences located in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; it is considered one of the world's main public health research institutions.

In this company I have been designing interfaces of systems used by thousands of medics, improving the user experience, digital transformation, and UX strategy. The UNASUS system was created by the Ministry of Health in 2010 to provide training education for health professionals.

United Nations
Senior User Experience Consultant
March 2021 - August 2021 (6 months)
Brasil

The United Nations Office on Drugs and Crime is a United Nations office that was established in 1997 as the Office for Drug Control and Crime Prevention.

I've worked in the "Custody Hearing System". It's a project to register people who have suffered violence or torture, or in social vulnerability.

With studies and research with users, I developed the information architecture so that users can use the system quickly and simply;

United Nations
Senior User Experience Consultant

May 2017 - September 2018 (1 year 5 months)

Brasília Area, Brazil

The United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO) is a specialized agency of the United Nations aimed at promoting world peace and security through international cooperation in education, arts, sciences, and culture

I have been working on the "Educação Livre" project (that means "Education Free"). It's a project to bring education to youth people, in social vulnerability.

Engesoftware Tecnologia S.A Senior Product Designer (UX/UI) October 2017 - July 2018 (10 months)

Brasília e Região, Brasil

The Regional Federal Courts (in Portuguese, "Tribunais Regionais Federais", commonly called TRFs) are the courts of appeal of Federal Courts of Brazil. They represent the second-instance courts of the Brazilian Federal Justice system.

At Eng tech, acting as a contractor in TRF I worked at the interface and design team to develop the TRF Design System, restructuring navigation and aesthetics and improving information architecture.

Fóton

UX Consultant

November 2016 - March 2018 (1 year 5 months)

Brasília Area, Brazil

One of my most important digital design work was for a digital bank app for "Banco da Amazônia", in Brazil.

In this app I was responsible to do the basic UX discovery research, I have made all the interaction design, like information architecture, and also, I made the User interface design, and the HTML and CSS customization.

I had made the usability tests with the all the prototypes, and now the developers are doing their job, and sometimes we still discuss some improvements for the app.

This project for Banco da Amazônia was awarded, in the categories "Channel Modernization, New Mobile Banking, Extra Cash Web", by the Efinance Award.

The Efinance Award aims to identify and highlight the most important projects in the Information and Communication Technology area of financial companies in Brazil.

Cidadania4u (Cidadania Italiana e Portuguesa) Senior Product Designer March 2017 - December 2017 (10 months) Brasil

Cidadania4u is an amazing company and is the largest company specializing in Italian and Portuguese citizenship recognition processes in Brazil. They use proprietary technology to ensure a faster, more transparent, and more secure process.

At Cidadania4U, as a senior UX Specialist, was responsible for designing interfaces for a complex system and an app that is used by thousands of different types of users. Part of the work was improving the user experience and UX strategy.

Sicoob Confederação

Senior User Experience and Strategic Designer, UX Leader December 2016 - July 2017 (8 months)

Brasília Area, Brazil

SICOOB is the Brazilian Credit Cooperative System, and It is a cooperative financial organization in Brazil that offers various banking services to its members, including loans, savings accounts, and insurance products.

At SICOOB I was responsible for working on implementing user experience standards, helping to improve products like apps, systems, and websites user experience, and other services.

United Nations

Senior UX Designer & FrontEnd Developer, Strategic Designer September 2014 - October 2016 (2 years 2 months)

Brasília Area, Brazil

The United Nations Development Program (UNDP) is a United Nations agency tasked with helping countries eliminate poverty and achieve sustainable economic growth and human development.

In United Nations for Development Program, as a Senior User Experience Designer, I've helped to create and improve the public debates platform of "Pensando o Direito", and also I created and implemented the website. In this project, I worked on user experience planning, screen design, and coding (HTML / CSS).

The debates involve citizens interested in discussing projects or draft laws, with the aim of complementing or even replacing traditional forms of elaboration, such as the formation of commissions of jurists.

Surittec Tecnologia
UX Consultant
March 2015 - July 2016 (1 year 5 months)

Surittec is a technology company that specializes in providing innovative solutions for various industries.

As a consultant of User Experience and Strategic Design, I helped to develop the design of websites, and also created startups' visual identity.

MAIS VIDA SOLUÇÕES EM SAÚDE. Product Design & UX Consultant March 2015 - February 2016 (1 year) Brasília e Região, Brasil

Mais Vida Soluções em Saúde is a health solutions company that provides comprehensive and innovative services to improve the health and well-being of its clients. With a focus on quality and customer satisfaction, the company

aims to make a positive impact on people's lives through its offerings.

The challenge of developing an experience for hospital care, combining agility and humanization. One of the biggest challenges is ensuring that the user interface is easy to use and understand for a diverse range of users, including patients, healthcare providers, and administrators.

Organización de Estados Iberoamericanos -OEI-UX Designer, Information Architect, Art Director, FrontEnd Developer January 2012 - February 2014 (2 years 2 months)

Brasília Area, Brazil

The Organization of Ibero-American States (Portuguese: "Organização de Estados Iberoamericanos") is an international organization made up of 23 member states of Iberian languages-speaking countries, mainly Spanish and Portuguese nations in Europe and the Americas, as well as one member in Africa.

At OEI, working as consulting in FNDE I worked at the interface and design team to develop the FNDE website, restructuring navigation and aesthetics, improving information architecture. I also worked with the integration of communication and interface departments, creating internal and external advertising campaigns.

Universidade de Brasília
UX Designer & FrontEnd Developer
November 2007 - April 2012 (4 years 6 months)
Brasília Area, Brazil

The University of Brasilia offers free public education of excellence for Brazilian and foreign students, with a humanistic, embrace, and plural perspective of citizens' rights.

Working at Cespe/UnB, I was responsible for the development of systems, responsible for information architecture, UX design, usability, accessibility, following the new government regulations, planning, and creation of design and implementation

Organizações Paulo Octávio
UX Designer, Art Director
April 2007 - November 2007 (8 months)

Brasília Area, Brazil

I work closely with cross-functional teams, including marketing, operations, and IT, to identify areas where the user experience can be improved.

CTIS

UX Designer & FrontEnd Developer January 2007 - November 2007 (11 months)

CTIS is a SONDA Corporate Wellness Innovation and technology that boost the team's performance, with solutions that, through technologies such as AI, IoT, and gamification, allow analyzing employees' habits and generate actions that improve their performance, well-being, and quality of life.

Development of UX for systems and websites, responsible for information architecture, UX design, usability, accessibility, following the new government regulations, planning, and creation of design and implementation.

AgênciaClick Art Director for web January 2006 - March 2007 (1 year 3 months)

Isobar delivers experience-led transformation and digital and creative solutions for clients globally. They have an extensive client roster across verticals, leveraging technology expertise, Global Innovation, and award-winning creative thinking.

As a short-period contractor, was responsible for designing and developing the design for systems and websites, information architecture, and the beginning of studies in user experience design, usability, and accessibility as well, also was responsible for art direction for websites and systems.

Grupo TV1 Contract Web Designer 2007 - 2007 (less than a year) Brasília e Região, Brasil

As a short-period contractor, was responsible for designing and developing the design for systems and websites, information architecture, and the beginning of studies in user experience design, usability, and accessibility as well. Working closely with the bank's marketing and communication teams to ensure that all visual elements are consistent with the bank's overall brand strategy and guidelines.

Cast group
UX Designer & FrontEnd Developer
2004 - 2006 (2 years)
Brasília Area, Brazil

Web Designing and development of the design for systems and websites, for information architecture, the beginning of studies in user experience design, usability, and accessibility as well.

NJobs Comunicação Interativa Junior Web Designer February 2002 - September 2003 (1 year 8 months) Brasília, Distrito Federal Junior development of the design for systems and websites, for information architecture, the beginning of studies in user experience design, usability, and accessibility as well.

Education

Faculdade UnYLeYa

Master of Business Administration (M.B.A.) in Design Thinking, Business Administration and Management, General \cdot (2016 - 2017)

IESB

Associate's Degree, Communication and Media Studies · (2002 - 2006)

Centro Universitário ICESP

Associate's Degree, Communication and Media Studies · (2008 - 2010)